Corona, CA

linkedin.com/in/KyleTurchik

Kyle Turchik

Full Portfolio: kturchik.github.io

kturchik@sbcglobal.net

(951) 316-1112

Game UI Programmer

Inspired programmer with 2 years of game industry experience emphasizing UI/UX development for consoles, PC, mobile and VR/AR applications. Proven leader driven by collaboration with multidisciplinary teams in an iterative and agile environment. Recognized for elevating professional projects with commitment to quality and innovation.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Cum Laude

California State Polytechnic University, Pomona, CA

Major GPA: 3.6/4.0

EXPERIENCE

INFINITY WARD | *UI Scripter - Call of Duty*

10/2018 - Present

Prototype, implement, and expand a wide array of UI related features and core UI systems, from frontend menus to gameplay elements, using C++, Lua, and Infinity Ward's proprietary UI layout tool.

- ♦ Commended for working face-to-face with designers and artists to ensure quality deliverables by providing feedback, solving technical roadblocks, and identifying all technical requirements for implementation.
- ♦ Identify design tool and code base limitations and optimize or develop systems to facilitate new UI designs.
- ♦ Create custom UI widgets and interface with gameplay and network systems in a proprietary C++ engine.
- ♦ Work with localization systems and implement UI features with internationalization in mind.
- Participate in code reviews, promoting reusable, maintainable, and extensible UI widgets and systems.
- Debug UI issues, taking initiative to work with gameplay and engine programmers to fix complex problems.

EPSILON SYSTEMS SOLUTIONS | *Computer Programmer II (Part-time)*

10/2018 - Present

Implement UX designs and frameworks for VR/AR solutions used by military and corporate training programs.

- Research and provide expertise to improve UX development procedures and pipelines for VR/AR platforms.
- ♦ Architect enhancements to development frameworks used for robust and rapid storyboarding and iteration.

WAREPLAI | Game Programmer (Contract)

01/2018 - 08/2018

Created core gameplay features for augmented reality games using Unity with Vuforia and ARKit/Core.

- ◆ Developed a successful game prototype that achieved 235% of its Kickstarter goal. (tiny.cc/ReignOfCthulhu)
- ♦ Collaborated with stakeholders to integrate assets and wireframes for multiple platforms and resolutions.
- ♦ Enhanced performance and memory efficiency on mobile devices by profiling and optimizing code.

BLIZZARD ENTERTAINMENT | Software Engineer Intern

06/2017 - 09/2017

Developed, from prototype to implementation, a rich single-page web application using JavaScript with WebGL.

- Exceeded expectations by proposing and prototyping a new feature that became the project's centerpiece.
- ♦ Created a 3D rendered display of large real-time data streams from Protocol Buffers over WebSockets.
- ♦ Solved a critical framerate limitation using object pooling and object-oriented patterns with WebGL.
- ♦ Architected maintainable systems using reflection techniques to integrate with evolving databases/APIs.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Augmented Realms | AR Tabletop RPG Simulator

12/2017

♦ Built tools for a procedural mesh-based level editor shared live over a multiuser network. (Unity)

Red Dwarf | *VR Space Sim Game*

05/2017

♦ Implemented world space UI, weapon physics, and player controls using SteamVR and VRTK. (Unity)

Elemental Fury | VR Multiplayer Game ("3rd Place Overall" at BeachHacks 2017)

04/2017

Battle of the Bards | Rhythm/RPG Game ("2nd Place Overall" & "Best Game" at HackPoly 2017)

02/2017

ORGANIZATIONS

International Game Developer Association | Board Member

09/2018 - Present

Student Game Developer Alliance (sqda.io) | Founder, Outreach Director Cal Poly Pomona Game Design & Development Club | President

02/2017 - Present 03/2016 - 06/2017

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: (Proficient) C# ♦ C++ ♦ Lua (Prior Experience) Java ♦ JavaScript ♦ Python

Tools: Unity 5+ ♦ Visual Studio ♦ Perforce ♦ Git ♦ Unreal Engine 4 ♦ WPF ♦ OpenGL ♦ JIRA ♦ Confluence **Competencies:** UI/UX Implementation ♦ Object-Oriented Design ♦ Optimization ♦ Memory Management

♦ Agile/Scrum ♦ 3D Graphics/Math ♦ Network Programming ♦ AR/VR ♦ OA Testing/Profiling